ABIODUN ABDULLATEEF

Software Developer (Frontend)
Yomlateef@yahoo.com | +2347059651794 | Github

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A self-taught, enthustiastic software developer specializing in front-end development, skilled in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+) and React to name a few. Focused on building responsive, mobile first web applications with elegant user interface and writing clean, testable, efficient and reusable codes. Exceptional flexibility as well as a keen desire to improve and develop new skills. Excellent at reviewing existing codes and can consult on possible improvements.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.

Frameworks: REACT, Bootstrap4, JQuery, TailwindCSS.

Cloud Platform: AWS (Cognito, Lambda, S3, Cloudfront)

Backend: Node JS, Learning Golang*

Preprocessor: Sass.

Others: A11y, User Interface Design (Figma)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

February 2020 to present – Lead Front-end Developer

TERAWORK

{HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node JS, AWS (Cognito, Lambda, S3, Cloudfront), Docker }

- Writing internal documentations and guides
- Enforcing code quality, style-guides and best practices.
- Managing communications between designer and frontend developers
- Creating frontend development workflow, deployment process and quality assurance
- Researched and Implemented Search Engine Optimizations (SEO) which improved visibility by over 70%
- Worked on React Performance and bundle size optimization

{HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, Redux }

- Worked with a team of 4 to port the entire codebase from a monolithic application to microservice and Single Page Application (SPA).
- Translate UI Designs and Mockups into components
- Code optimization improvements, maintenance and refactoring of existing application
- Development of modular, testable and scalable software components
- Developed admin dashboard with analytics and process management

February 2018 to March 2019 - Freelance Front-end Developer

- Built information websites for companies and agencies (GlobalSpace Nigeria, GameOfWords)
- Converted HTML templates into Drupal 8 themes
- Created UI designs and mockups using Figma
- Implemeted Schema markup for better structuring of website data.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

July 2018 - October 2018 Front-end Developer Nanodegree

Udacity & Google

2015 - 2017 ND Science Laboratory Technology upper credit

Yaba College of Technology, Yaba.

SOCIALS

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/abayomibiodun/

Twitter - https://twitter.com/YelloowDev

Github - https://github.com/yawmiej